To be honest, I struggled justifying it
to myself and thinking like, well, what
what are we going to publish every
month? What are we going to keep putting
out to justify our subscription? But
that's just not
how that works, particularly not for
these kind of utility products. It took
me a while to sort of kind of come round
to the idea. We went in with a very low
$20 a year subscription price cuz I just
thought that's what sounded fair.
>> Welcome to Launched. I'm Charlie Chapman
and today I'm excited to bring you the
creator of Teleprompter Pro and the
just-released app Captions, Joe Allen.
Joe, welcome to the show.
>> Hello.
>> So, before we get into Teleprompter Pro
and your whole backstory, I always try
to start with a really quick elevator
pitch of what the app is so that people
kind of know where we're going. This
one's kind of funny because the app's
called Teleprompter Pro.
Uh so, maybe a little self-explanatory.
>> Yeah, I struggled to do that sort of
pitch without using the word
teleprompter. Um so, maybe I'll explain
that first. It's the thing that you see
the news presenters reading on the
camera, right? That's a teleprompter.
And Teleprompter Pro is an app that
allows sort of creators and studios um
to have their own teleprompter and and,
you know, produce better content and
more engaging things, whether it's a um
video or a speech or you know, wedding
speeches, things like that. Um yeah,
it's a little pocket version of a
full-size studio teleprompter.
>> And when you say that, you mean because
it's on your phone or your iPad as
opposed to it's not a physical device.
>> Correct, yeah. Yeah.
>> Awesome. All right. So, uh let's kick
this off the same way I always kick off
the show, which is uh I have three
questions for you, which is where are
you from? Uh do you have a formal
education related to what you do? And
then what was your career backstory
before you started building
Teleprompter?
>> Okay, I'm from a very boring town near
London. So, I I normally say London if I
meet a stranger.
Um but I'm actually from a boring town
just outside. Um but we invented the
fiber optic and the blue asthma inhaler.
That's my I'm sure I've told you that
many times.
>> Oh, yeah. That's usually the go-to.
Usually, I always say
>> need to know where I am, look that up.
Tell me it, I'll be there. I didn't go
to university. I don't have a degree or
anything. Um
but um I I do have some education in
like media studies and film studies,
which doesn't really mean much cuz it's
not it's not a degree. It's like a
2-year thing after high school. It's
It's not much. Um
but I suppose it's sort of in the
industry, right? Um that that's what I
wanted to get into.
>> It's very interesting how many people
I've talked to on the show that their
background is in
film or animation or something
specifically like that. I think there's
something about the sort of indie
side of mobile app development or maybe
the iOS, you know, Apple's kind of the
intersection of of science and or
computer science and liberal arts or
whatever that that does that. But yeah,
it it actually seems really relevant in
a in an interesting way.
>> Yeah, I suppose especially
I suppose like yeah, film and like you
say animation, it's one of those things
where
you can do it with like a hundred
million dollars, right? And that's what
you see growing up and you think, "Oh, I
I I want to
do that." And you actually can just do
that with a pocket camera or or, you
know,
I suppose now you can do animation on
iPad and things like that. So, it's one
of those interesting things where you
can
aspire to these like great iconic works
of art
and be able to do them at home in your
bedroom as well. I wonder if that's a
a sort of similar thing for like um
particularly app development, but
software in general where
yeah, we have these works of art that
you can
>> a blend of, you know, art and science,
right? Like so much of film is actually
really technical, not exciting.
>> going to use?
>> Yeah, right. Exactly. Yeah, obsession
with gear. Uh
>> Yeah.
>> There's a surprising amount of overlap.
And I guess also, like we're talking
about here, uh
the
there's a thriving indie scene in film
as well, which is about how can you get
the same level of artistry
um at a way smaller budget with a small
team and do something that's still
impactful. Uh yeah, that's interesting.
Okay, so yeah, so you have a background
in in media then.
Um and then is that what your career
took off in then? Was that what you were
doing initially?
>> Well, it's interesting actually cuz
yeah, immediately after um
it we call it college here, but it's not
university. Immediately after college,
um I had sort of started doing
freelance-y style Actually, it was while
I was still there even. Um
camera work, right? I had a
$500 DSLR and I thought I was the
world's best camera person, so I
>> Oh, yeah. This is the age of the
uh
5D Mark II where all of a sudden you
could shoot video with like
>> Yeah.
>> real lenses
>> Exactly that.
>> under, you know, $5,000 and it's like,
"Whoa."
>> Yeah. So, I I put myself out there as
like video creator person, right? Um and
that's sort of where Teleprompter Pro
was born. Um but I did actually have
like a real jobby job for, I think,
seven or so years. Um
And it was along the same lines. It was
a little bit more um
web web design and
and um
sort of graphic design-y. Um it was for
like an events company. We did their
websites and and their sort of on-stage
graphics and things.
>> And you just got into the web because
you were working with them and you're
like, "I can figure out computers" or
you are
>> it it's something I had done at school
as well. I was kind of into that idea.
So that was that was a fun job to get as
a first job, right? And I I I enjoyed
that. Um
But yeah, so I did have these sort of
two things going on where one well was
more like
um
video production type thing, but it was
kind of a hobby that I just enjoyed
doing and I liked buying the gear. Um
and then yeah, I had a real job in
actual
design and a little bit of web
development and things like that. Um
and that's the one I had to quit to go
full-time with Teleprompter Pro.
>> So okay, so in this mode,
uh where did Teleprompter Pro come from
then? Were you already doing mobile apps
or did it start with this?
>> It's a funny story really. There's
there's kind of two parts to it. I
remember
when I was at at um
like secondary school, high school, I
had really supportive teachers,
particularly the the head teacher. Um
We just sort of had this relationship
where we sort of chatted about just
stuff. Um and he kind of knew the things
I was into and we was on a we was on a
trip.
Um and
mobile apps were kind of new. I think
this was 2009. Um so
>> No, yeah, very that's like
>> Still kind of new, but it's not this
week's news.
>> Right.
>> Yes. Yeah, yeah, so people knew.
Um
And we were just chatting and and one of
his questions was like um
are you are you not interested in these
new mobile apps? Um
And my answer was like, well yeah, but
they're kind of difficult to to develop
for, right? Especially in 2009, right?
And I didn't even have a Mac. So my
my 30 minutes of research and like, oh,
how can I make an iPhone app, you know,
the one of the beer drinking apps or
what are the others? Fart noises. Yeah,
it was just like a dead end. Like, oh,
you need a Mac and you need to know this
weird language that's kind of not really
you can't Google so much and it
it kind of came to a dead end there. But
when he prompted me on that trip, it
kind of
put the idea back in my mind, if that
makes sense. Um
and for some reason I've always
remembered that as the moment where
I was sort prompted to give it a real
go, you know, maybe I can do this thing.
And that wasn't like the the week that I
made Teleprompter Pro, but I I
I did have a Mac at that point and I
downloaded Xcode and just started
playing. So I think that was my
um
entry into
making a mobile app, specifically iPhone
um at the time.
Um and then Teleprompter Pro came from
that freelance work that I was doing
where we
we kind of needed a teleprompter, but
not necessarily a teleprompter. We just
needed someone to read their lines.
>> Yeah. Was this like a commercial kind of
thing?
>> It was a kind of yeah, it was this weird
guy in my town who thought he could make
a television pilot
for some idea that he had. It was awful.
It was just awful. There's so much more
to that story.
>> So you knew obviously you knew
teleprompters existed.
>> I think so, but it didn't really even
come to mind. What happened was I was
too cool to like write it on a piece of
paper and hold it, right? That's that's
no.
So my my new first generation iPad which
at the time didn't really have many uses
in real life, you know, it had the a
clock and a calendar. Uh I thought,
"Aha, I can type this into
Apple Pages and scroll it
with my fingers, right? That's so much
better than paper, surely."
Um
and it kind of wasn't, you know,
scrolling on Apple Pages on a first gen
iPad was kind of
not really that great, but it worked. Um
and that's where Teleprompter Pro came
from, basically. Um
I I had a bunch of apps on the store.
They were all kind of junk, just
projects that I had fun making. Um and
that one just had noticeably more
downloads.
>> Well, you say that one, but at this
stage that you're describing, you know,
you have you're using Pages,
presumably with the font really big and
you're scrolling.
>> I did make it into a
an app on the store.
>> What was the impetus for uh Pages isn't
working for me?
You know, was there like something
you're like, "I wish it did this." and
you finally you're like, "You know what?
I'm just going to make a
cheap small app."
>> Yeah, I remember like just struggling to
have a black background even.
>> Ah, that's I was wondering if that's
what it was. Cuz I don't know if
>> Yeah, just stuff like that.
>> do that. Maybe now you can with dark
mode.
>> I don't know if you remember the iPad
launch marketing.
Um but it it was kind of similar to the
early iPhone marketing where it was just
a bunch of cool apps, you know, quickly
showing on their on their TV ad. And one
of them was that um the clapperboard.
The the
>> Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> thing. I thought, "Aha, this is cool."
I'm I'm going to have a a clapperboard
on my iPad. And uh this teleprompter
thing. Um and I made a clapperboard app
as well. Again, without really
understanding I I knew what the primary
purpose, you know, the noise and the and
that the video.
>> Um but I didn't know what those numbers
meant. I just put a clock there.
>> Right.
>> I just made an app.
Um so yeah, I had this like suite of
just random project apps. One was a
clapperboard and then yeah, I I made a
teleprompter which at the time you
couldn't even really adjust the like
speed or anything. It would just sort of
moved some text up. Um but it got
downloads.
>> Yeah. Okay, so it started getting
So it sounds like you have a you had a
bunch of little apps. Did this one
immediately jump out as
oh, maybe there's like an audience here?
>> Yeah, I think so. I I distinctly
remember thinking like what like this
weird this one's getting more downloads.
Am I just in a good position on the
store or something?
Am I not sort of understanding some
different keyword and people are
accidentally downloading it, but but no,
it was
it seemed to be the first that I'd hit
on that actually had a genuine use in
life, right? Um other than my random
games that I'd made or or that cap
aboard that didn't really do much other
than made a noise.
>> And probably worth pointing out here
that
you got the name
presumably right off the bat,
teleprompter. Is that right?
>> No.
>> No?
>> Oh, what was the original name?
>> Well, back in those days, I think you
could have like 100 characters
in the app title. It it it got a very
short uh maybe 10 years ago. Um
but in those days you could have a much
longer so it was called like
teleprompter video professional
Autocue's a brand name in the UK for
video creator It was a stupid long
title.
>> That's So, were you you Were you keyword
stuffing like intentionally for
marketing reasons at that point?
>> Yeah, but only in the same way that I I
sort of knew that was good thing to do.
I had
>> Yeah, yeah, understanding you're like a
kid basically at this point. But you're
used to seeing at that point already
Amazon, you know, products that have
just a thousand other
>> other apps had similar things and I
think it kind of worked. Um
And even in those days um if you're it
you would appear alphabetically in a
what's new page so it was it was
beneficial to start your app name with
an A.
>> Did you start with an A?
>> have even potentially called it a
teleprompter app
or something like that. I can't I I bet
I can find it. I'll I'll I'll message
you later with the full name. But But
no, no, we didn't didn't have a
particularly unique or strong keyword
name other than it just had a bunch of
keywords.
>> but when did you kind of collapse it
down to just teleprompter?
>> It wasn't
very long ago. It was within the last
five or 6 years when when that started
to matter.
App stores always sort of changing and
evolving, but it was
around about the time when
it became a thing is like, oh, a single
unique search term name that people are
going to type in, right?
>> We needed more.
>> is a good thing to have. And and it was
it was available in in one of the
English languages. I mean, we merged it.
>> If you go back to the point where it's
in the store and you recognize it's
starting to kind of tick up, it was good
enough, but it wasn't like you were
doing a bunch of extra curricular
marketing at that time. It was just
organically getting a decent amount of
downloads and presumably continuing
users.
>> Yeah, yeah, absolutely. Um we've never
ever had a day of zero revenue, ever. Um
and it's not to mean it made a whole
bunch of money. It was like a
$2.99 app for many, many years. Um
but that that alone was like, wow, this
this thing seems to be, you know, people
are paying for it and
you know, they're not complaining. You
know, it seems to be
a a
worthwhile sort of product that people
like.
Um
so yeah, it it was clear early on that
that it's a it was a concept that people
were were looking for at least.
>> Yeah.
So, did you
kind of at that point take it more
seriously as like this is a product and
start trying to do either marketing or
adding features to make it more
worthwhile or playing with the business
model or anything at that point?
>> Just
>> Just pull us out of this and be a little
meta here for a second. You know,
talking to the audience right now. Joe
is one of the most understated people
I've ever met.
Like
you probably already picked this up, but
he talks as if he's
this this random guy who like there's
nothing interesting about him and then
randomly he'll talk about like
dealing with bug reports from the
International Space Station or something
and you'll be like, what in the world?
And so I already am I'm prepared for
who knows what wild things I'm going to
So, don't let his uh you know, modesty
uh
>> Oh, well, I don't know anything about
it.
>> Uh
>> Yeah.
>> But, I can hear it in your voice even
there. You're like, "Ah, I don't want to
make this sound as cool as it actually
is."
Uh
>> No, it's if I don't know. I just I want
to be careful that I'm not like making
stories up cuz
I I've I don't know. It just I know what
we when you think back to like 15 years
ago, you're like, "Oh, yeah, I just I
did that and it went well and that's
what I did cuz I knew what to do." And
that's not how it goes.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> Um but, yeah, from from what I can
remember, I I I like the idea of like
having
a cool product, you know, and being able
to like release updates and announce
things. So, I don't know. That That was
cool. So,
I like that aspect of it, but I don't
know if I'd quite sort of
um committed to like, "Okay, this is a
thing that I'm going to do for 15 years
and this is our big thing." But, rather
that
um
it had some users, so it was kind of
cool that I could
do these
changes and updates and you know,
whatever people were requesting. It was
fun to then release that.
>> Were you using it yourself?
>> Occasionally, yeah. I I didn't do much
of that type of work, but um I did get
opportunities to do that. So, that was
certainly useful um just to like have a
day actually in the field doing these
things.
>> So, the primary driver of, you know,
your work then was
based on feedback you were getting from
users, like requests and stuff like
that?
>> Yeah, pretty much. Um and and at the
time I was kind of
stupid 19-year-old. Didn't really know
what I was doing in terms of like
software engineering. Um for a very,
very long time
um all of the data in the app was stored
in NSUserDefaults.
But, in a wild way, like the the keys
just had it would be like user script
one, user script two, user script three,
and I would just like loop through
those.
>> Oh, wow. Okay. Yeah.
>> It was just It worked perfectly, but it
was just when it came to like
introducing a new
um variable or something,
uh it was just a
It was just a whole lot of uh
un- undoing bad work and things. So, I
kind of struggled with turning into like
a real piece of software that I could
um iterate on and and and
you know, make meaningful
um updates to. But But that was my
thing. So, it was like, yeah, now
how can we introduce
a video recording option, you know, so
you could record a selfie video at the
same time. That took me a very long time
to figure out.
Um
but yeah, it certainly hadn't become
like this is our thing,
our product and our and our sort of
company now.
>> Well, when you're saying our, at this
stage it was still just you, right?
>> Yeah, I don't know why I'm saying our. I
think it's just cuz I'm thinking about
us now.
>> Uh yeah, as a company.
>> But But certainly at the time, no, I was
just a sort of 19, 20-year-old with this
app on the App Store.
>> At some point then,
you know, it it reached the point where
you did make that jump. What's the path
there? Like how How did you get to the
point where it was making enough money
that you could kind of make that that
jump?
>> That That kind of happened like on its
own
um in terms of like it got to
a revenue point where
it could sustain me at least. Um
it was very, very slow, um and I think
it probably just happened as the App
Store grew.
And you know, and I I wonder even if you
if you took that into consideration, um
the app itself might not have even grown
or it might have shrunk and grown at
different rates as I was just sort of
dipping in and out of
um working on it and doing other things
in in my life. Um
So, that kind of happened on its own
over
a few years. Um but then I was very very
slow to
commit to, "Okay, this is what I'm going
to do now with my life."
Um and I think it was just that sort of
fear of what if it
changes or goes wrong or I don't know I
don't know what I'm doing. I got
>> Yeah, I This is like a thing I think so
there are different types of people. I
think me and you are in in the same boat
where
we assume that literally everything is
happening to us and that we're not
responsible for for any of the success.
And when you're in that mode, I think
that's actually healthy in the App Store
in particular because there are a lot of
factors that can drive users towards you
that
like the I know people who, you know,
they they work on their app all the
time. They're always adding features and
they're attributing their growth to
to the features that they're adding. And
and that very well might be true. But
it's also possible that you know, I I've
talked to many people on the show in
fact that were doing that for a long
time. They had a business that was
growing and then
very suddenly the bottom drops out and
they have no idea why. And it turns out
there was some keyword that they were
ranking well for and a small change in
the algorithm or a tweak that they made
just caused the whole thing to just like
invert and then they had to do a bunch
of research.
It doesn't mean that your business is
going to fall apart, but it does mean
that like
uh you have to be aware of where that's
coming from if you want to solve it.
Uh and so yeah, I I very much understand
that. Also as somebody who has a side
project where sometimes it gets lots of
attention from me, sometimes it doesn't.
And it's it's not growing at like your
trajectory, but it's it sustains itself
and some of that is just
you know, I keep it solid and working
and I'm taking advantage of the fact
that the App Store is doing a lot of
that work for for So, yeah, I I
definitely understand. I think that's a
really healthy way to like look at the
App Store is
uh
it it's this sort of river with water
running through it, and you can kind of
tap into it, but the river can move.
It's a much bigger thing than you.
Uh you kind of
Yeah, need to understand that things can
change out from under you at any time.
>> Yeah, definitely. Yeah, so so it took me
um
probably another 5 years after
it would have been enough to sustain me
to actually end that full-time job.
Um and I'm sort of aware of it, but I I
certainly
was you know, I was in no rush to um
>> Yeah.
>> put all of my eggs in that basket.
>> Were you doing things during this time
or maybe immediately afterwards
specifically to make that more
sustainable? Like
I at some point I know you switched your
business model.
Uh you when we you know, where we left
off, you weren't really doing much
marketing. Did you start playing with
those kinds of things? Like what were
the things you were doing to kind of
make it a little bit more of a capital B
business?
>> A lot of of what I I did to sort of make
that happen um
was things like price increases and sort
of just being a bit more upfront about
okay, this is a paid product. You know,
there's you can use it for free, but
you know, that's just so you can try it
out and see if it fits in with you.
We're a paid product, and we're not
$2.99 anymore. We're I don't know. I
think when I when I quit my job, it was
like
$17.99, which to me was a lot of money
for an app, you know.
>> But your industry like you're selling
almost B2B
uh in terms of how a lot of people are
probably purchasing it. Like if you're
on a production like the cost of a
physical teleprompter, granted they're
going to have to use this with other
physical items, but like uh yeah, $17 is
like basically free in terms of a movie
budget, even a really low budget, you
know, production.
>> Yeah, a lot of that was sort of me
learning that and being confident enough
to to
you know, put our pricing a little bit
more along the lines of what we were
actually offering.
Um
And
I I'm just trying to think when we went
subscription, but that was that was
quite a while after I went full-time. Um
So, yeah, I think a lot of it was just
that actually understanding our position
in the
in the market. And then
sort of that doing that puts me in a
position where I have a little bit more
responsibility to
create a product that's sort of robust
and does the things that people need it
to do. Um
So, they kind of kind of went
hand-in-hand where, you know, I I
position us as a sort of serious thing
as a oh, I've actually got to make it.
>> You got to follow that up. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, I think that helped.
Um
yeah, and I I think it was about 2018
that I went full-time. And then 2020 is
when we went subscription.
>> So, what was the subscription transition
like? What drove you to do that? I mean,
I can guess. And then and then how did
you do that transition and how did it
go?
>> We'd done things in the past where I'd
I'd we would release like a new app and
that was the next version and you have
to sort of buy this new version, you
know.
>> essentially.
>> it's kind of not possible in the App
Store, right? We tried it.
>> app and it's entirely right? Did you
ever successfully
move people over? Like what were you
doing in-app things? Were you collecting
emails and sending like, "Hey, there's a
new version."
>> Yeah, we
we we had a
email list of our customers and yeah, we
would we would have in-app prompts and
and just all those things, but it it was
just a a mess, really.
I think you it can be done, right?
There's a couple of examples where
that's that's kind of their model, but
we weren't really at the scale that that
would work and I just didn't sort of
like it anyway. I avoided it for a long
time but subscription was the the right
move and we still we still have um
sort of
leftovers from pre-subscription. We
still have two apps where we used to
have a light and a paid, you know.
Um
that's kind of a difficult thing for us
to work around but but yeah,
subscription is the right way for us to
go.
>> That was why you switched over.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh the pain of doing up grade pricing is
is crazy. How did that go? Did you have
users upset? Did it was it just pretty
smooth?
>> Yeah, it it's kind of doesn't matter
what you do, people will get upset,
right? Cuz what we did was anyone who's
purchased you just access forever. Like
you what you paid for you full access
forever so
all of our customers they know
difference to them um but it we found
that most of the people that got upset
were those customers thinking that they
would be charged now and you know, it
was just a communication issue really.
>> Some of my favorite uh you know, bad
reviews I have on the store are
people being upset that it's a
subscription app and the literal first
thing is
or it's a yeah, like subscription, you
know, hacker garbage or scam or whatever
and then it says
>> Yeah.
>> Uh the very beginning will say great app
uh even though I'm grandfathered in and
they don't charge me, this is evil and
I'm against it. One star.
And I'm kind of like
you know, what you know, I I almost see
those as positive one star reviews like
if somebody's going to sort by one stars
and the one stars they see are like
uh They treated me very well. I just
don't like that this costs money.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh the app is good. I'm kind of like uh
I'm okay with customers seeing that, you
know. Um but yeah, it is it is
there's like a holy war kind of aspect
to subscriptions.
>> Yeah, so so we we had that um and I
think to be honest I struggled um
justifying it to myself.
Um I'm thinking like well, what what are
we going to publish every month?
You know, what what are we going to keep
putting out to justify our subscription,
but
you know, that's just not
how that works, particularly not for
these kind of utility um, products. It
took me a while to sort of kind of come
round to the idea. Um,
and again, we we went in with a very
low, like $20 a year subscription price
cuz I just thought that's what sounded
fair. I I'm I really was just picking
numbers from the sky.
>> Yeah.
>> But yeah, otherwise it was it was quite
smooth. We just used that um,
transaction receipt date to grandfather
everyone in. Um, and then anybody else
just saw the um, subscription payable.
And we still today offer a lifetime
price. Um, it's it's basically three and
a bit years um,
price in it. And
that seems to please most people. Um, so
it was
fairly smooth, you know, we
it feels like it was kind of rough cuz
you were you always receive the the
the heat directly, right? Or all the
complaints come to you and it sounds
like you've just sort of
done the worst thing in the world. But
but no, it it was it was certainly a
good move and it seemed to go pretty
pretty smoothly.
>> And then
after that,
was it pretty immediate like
okay, this is a little more sustainable.
Uh, now we can kind of
expand the business. We can get to the
part where you're saying we and us and
our
>> Yes, yeah, exactly. It's actually more
accurate.
I think I I was comfortable that it it
was a sustainable thing to be doing. Um,
for a while by that point. Um, I'm kind
of two years into being full-time and
maybe
seven years into it being my main source
of income.
Um, so I was quite happy with that at
that point. Um,
but I I yeah, you're right. It was about
then that that that gave me then the
opportunity to
expand a little bit and and you know,
things like customer support were
actually impacting my
life because I just had so many
messages to reply and things and then
you know, I
I I had a lot of um I cared a lot about
making sure ever people got the answer
they needed or were corrected about how
wrong they were. Um so that kind of kept
me up
for too long in the days.
>> Well, and it is like you were saying, if
you're charging a premium price, part of
the expectation there is
>> Yeah.
>> that there is support, right?
>> So a lot of
questions we get have to are just super
simple like two-word answers or it's
like oh, you just need to press this or
you've you've got your orientation lock
on, that's why it's not going landscape.
Um and I I sort of feared that that
would turn into one-star reviews or or
just someone abandoning the products and
I don't know why I had so much care for
like individual cases, but it was just
it was important to me and and that sort
of consumed my
my um working day um for a long time. So
yeah, our first hire was
um
customer support, take care of all of
that and and
I could go back to trying to build
software however I could figure it out.
>> Was that like a freeing feeling once you
get that going?
>> Yeah, I think so. It It very quickly
um became not my problem at all.
>> Yeah.
>> I would maybe get one or two really
weird edge case questions
or just decisions like oh, should we
just give this person the the pro
upgrade cuz of XYZ and just yeah.
Um but yeah, that quite quickly it just
sort of took all of that away from me.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> Yeah, email is is a job, but it often
isn't the job, you know, but it can be
like, "Oh, I got a lot done today." cuz
you answered like 12 emails that each
took an hour somehow.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh yeah, I get that.
>> But since then, you've you've expanded
the team. Like, what size are you at
right now?
>> Uh it's four of us now, including me.
So, me plus three.
>> And what how has that changed kind of
the trajectory of the company going
from, you know, just you to you plus,
you know, a team of people?
>> It's interesting cuz um
from from just the inside, my
experience, it feels like
oh, it it's it's the same, right? We've
got mostly the same product, and we're
kind of putting out the same amount of
updates and things for customers, and
we're we're
essentially doing the same thing. But
now it just for some reason takes four
of us, which
I I
took me a while to sort of come to terms
with, but what I've realized, um and
certainly if I start like looking at
actual numbers, is I if I look at
certain graphs, I can see the points in
which I hired people. Um and it's
because like, "Oh, okay, now I can focus
on
um
how should we position our upgrade
product? You know, when do we show the
paywall? What do we think is fair to put
behind the paywall and in front and we
could run experiments on it." And I was
free to do that cuz it kind of takes
time, right? It it's
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> It allowed me to make those product
decisions without having to do
engineering stuff just to like
fix a bug that came in iOS 16 or
something. Um so, certainly the last um
two years, which is when
we got a Swift engineer to take care of
actual software, um we've been able to
sort of grow in those ways
that
I always had at the bottom of my
priority list, like
you know, I
do I build this cool new feature or do I
just see where the paywall should
appear? And I I kind of don't like those
things anyway. I I I
I have to be very
careful and sort of mindful of how we're
doing those things. So, that was always
at the bottom of my list.
And having
an excellent team take care of
those things, like engineering and
features and and you know, what are we
going to build next, lets me spend a lot
of time really being considerate about,
"Okay, how do we grow
the things that we might be kind of
ignoring, you know?"
>> And what are some of those things that
have
have moved the needle or didn't in a way
that you thought it would?
>> a nice onboarding for
probably 13 years,
our onboarding was just a uh
a sign-in, you know, login and create an
account.
>> You're It's like you're speaking
directly to me. This has been the
the top of my should-do priority list
for probably 10 years.
>> you know,
it's kind of it is important, right? Cuz
it it it as you say, moves the needle
for like growth and and
s-
things like revenue and retention and
things, but
but really, yeah, I want to be building
the things that people are asking for.
They're not asking for a better
onboarding.
>> Especially with a subscription, but even
even without,
it's like I'm always thinking about the
current users.
>> Mhm.
>> Um and I I don't take the time to think
about
which quite frankly is the majority of
my users are new users, right? Like most
people try it for a little while and
then and then bounce. Uh whether free or
trial or whatever.
And so, it's not just like especially
living in, you know, RevenueCat land,
it's easy to only be thinking like,
"Yeah, that can improve my conversion
rate and all this stuff," which is
I'm not obviously not saying that that's
bad, but even from a pure like wholesome
product level,
I get so many customer support emails
that are like,
"How can I create a you know a custom
mix of ambient noises inside of my app?"
And it's like, that's a feature in the
app.
>> Yeah.
>> And if I literally just had a little a a
quick slide that was just like, "You can
do this thing." Even if it doesn't
really show them how to do it, just the
fact that it says that it's something
you can do can go a long way to improve
the amount of people who find that
feature, right?
>> Absolutely.
>> So it really is like
good product work, but it's not
uh
it's not satisfying in the same way that
I think a lot of sort of
product-oriented people
>> Mhm.
>> want work to be satisfying.
>> I guess it's just one of those things
like
I struggled with sort of feeling bad
about optimizing for those things cuz it
feels like, well, that
What am I actually doing here? This is
for me now, not for for users. Um
but ultimately they they do
they find features, like you say, and
then you know, there's
there's an opportunity to sort of
put them on some rails and just sort of
say, "Here's where this is, here's where
this is, and you can
do these things if you want."
>> And onboarding, so that was that one
that like moved the needle for you
business-wise?
>> Absolutely, yeah. I can I can
point to you on a graph where that
happened. It was it was big for us.
>> Here okay, I'll earn my paycheck here
for a second. So literally just this
morning, uh I I saw a feature that we
are rolling out currently to our charts,
which means everybody listening probably
it's already out to everybody. But we
have a little thing where you can
annotate your graphs now.
>> I didn't know that.
>> You could mark I you didn't know cuz I I
literally found out this morning. Uh but
you can mark,
you know,
I hi- you know, this is when we hired
Greg
>> Yeah.
>> or this is when Apple featured us or
whatever. And
>> Yeah.
>> It's I literally had to then prepare for
this uh interview, but I already have,
you know all these ideas in my head of
like, "Oh, I need to go in and mark when
this podcast feature happened or
whatever." And it's funny listening to
you say you keep saying like uh "I can
point on the graph." And I'm like,
"That's like an interesting exercise to
to do." Obviously, whether you're
RevenueCat or not, you know, it's nice
that you can mark it on the graph, but
just to go back and actually like have I
guess this is another one of those like
when you hire people you have a little
time to do self-reflection, but it's a
good self-reflection exercise to go back
and like
think of the things you thought were
important and like look for the signals.
Like are were they actually? And then if
you see a weird signal, see if you can
pinpoint the real cause of it.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, that's pretty cool. So yeah, so
onboarding was one.
I know another one that the talk that
you're about to give at Deep Dish, which
I haven't seen yet, so I don't know the
answers to
what you're going to say, but you're
giving a talk that has to do a lot with
your sort of email marketing that you
did with with
Teleprompter. So can you talk about like
what that was and how that's been
beneficial for you?
>> Yeah, um it's top of mind, so I've got
lots of nice sound bites for you.
But
I'm quite convinced that that
is the single most important thing I
ever did for
my career in this company.
>> Wow, more than the ASO?
>> Absolutely, yeah. I mean
>> Wow, okay.
>> It's hard for me to know obviously if if
I'd gone a different way then maybe,
um but
from very early on,
um
I I just sort of asked people for an
email address in in my random apps that
I was making.
>> As part of onboarding?
>> Well, I didn't I didn't have onboarding.
It was just like a
thing that popped up. But yeah, I I
think that was just because I liked the
idea of being able to like announce cool
things to lots of people.
Um and it's just like obviously it
kind of pointless early on with my just
total random, barely functional apps
that I'd made. Um,
but what that meant was, even very early
versions of Teleprompter Pro,
we have this nice customer list that we
can we can speak to. So, what that means
is when we did do like we tried upgrade
pricing and doing different
>> versions of the app. It was actually
possible at least then.
>> Yeah, it was possible. We could send an
email and with everyone would know and
people would be able to we'd steer
people in the right direction. Um, and I
think it's one of those things that
allowed me, um, like how you were saying
earlier, to
have a bit more confidence that my
entire life isn't just balancing on like
the App Store search algorithm. Even
though it kind of is,
if there's kind of some temporary
roadblock or something does change, we
do have that opportunity to kind of
communicate or just like,
"Hey, we've had to change our name for
some crazy reason." And like,
you know, we're not starting from square
one. Um,
and it's just yeah, there's there's lots
of examples of that, but that
that's been
really important for us.
>> Do you use that for
growth then? Like, are are you
re-engaging, you know, churned customers
and seeing them coming back?
>> A little bit. More along the lines of,
you know, retention, I guess.
>> It's a strange one cuz we don't actually
even though we it's a kind of
big part of how we've been able to grow,
we don't go too deep on like,
like you say, re-engaging churned
subscribers or or or anything like that,
but we do things like when they cancel,
we'll ask them why, you know, and and
just
gives us a lot of nice feedback. Um,
or we'll ask them
>> through an email?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Ah, okay, okay. That makes sense.
>> A couple of days after signing up, we'll
just ask them, "Have you got any
questions?" or
you know, thumbs up, thumbs down, and
then
we we will personally come back and just
sort of
chat to customers who have questions,
and that's that's led to a lot of either
great um product ideas or or just sort
of fun partnerships or
connections we've been able to make. So,
that that's been good.
>> Yeah, how do you contribute to growth?
Like, wouldn't this all be downstream
from
>> Those things, yeah, I wouldn't
necessarily say are super
um growth contributors, but they've been
very good at sort of guiding us in our
general direction, which ultimately, I
suppose, means growth. Um but but
specifically for growth, we've been able
to
um
when we have like
something like a uh
I'm just trying to think of a good
example. When when we went subscription,
um you know, we could put a bit of a
discount and tell everyone, "Hey, we're
>> Yeah.
>> If you've been on the fence, try our
subscription cuz it's cheap this week,
you know?" And that that gives us a big
big boost, and we still see that bump
every year because
that's when we sent a bunch of people.
>> Do you do discounts often, like outside
of that?
>> About once a year. Not necessarily like
Black Friday or anything. Um we've we've
tried Black Friday, and it it it works.
Um I I just don't want to be
um you know, I don't want an email from
Joe Allen to just be like
"50% off. Get 10% off. Ends tomorrow.
Don't Don't lose out, you know?" Um so,
we we're mindful not to do that.
>> And you mentioned it's an email from Joe
Allen. So, in I've noticed this looking
through your app reviews recently, a
surprising amount of them say the
creator, Joe.
>> Yeah.
>> Which is interesting, cuz I I I never
thought of you as much
You know, you think of like Marco Arment
or some of these David Smith like some
of these like kind of well-known in the
iOS cuz they have podcasts or you know,
whatever. Uh and you link those two
together, but at least talking to you I
always got the idea that like
Teleprompter Pro is this sort of
industry
app. Uh but it sounds like you have made
a personal connection in some way. Was
that intentional?
>> I've not really thought about it, but I
think you're probably right. Um and we
do we kind of position ourselves how you
describe as a as an entity rather than a
person who has an app, right?
Um I I often
think
um along the lines of like um Procreate.
You know, we're we are this product,
right? And but yeah, a lot of the
communications come from me.
Um so I think
some of
like what you've read the the App Store
reviews, people are kind of happy to
have heard from me or they feel like
we've had this sort of
connection and we've been able to
form a sort of you know, like a
relationship over
this thing that they've asked for and I
come back and say, "Oh yeah, we can do
that." Or
you know, "Have you thought about doing
it this way around?"
Um
and yeah, a lot of those have come from
we've sent like a welcome.
Thanks for downloading Teleprompter Pro.
And people just reply. It's been It's
been great. Almost everything that we
try, we've been able to at least
have people see it.
You know, not necessarily be successful
or make a bunch of revenue.
Um but things that we've tried, we've
been able to send lots of people that
way and we get either get feedback or
it's gone well and you know, I just
don't think I can't think of how we
could have
got to where we are now without having
that in place of a
a list of customers that we can send a
nice message to.
>> Another thing I'm
interested in is I think whenever we
first met
a a few years ago, you were kind of
starting this
I want to go out into the into the
field, so to speak. Now, obviously, when
we met, we were at developer
conferences, but I know you go to
uh like film industry conferences like
NAB and stuff as well. Uh
I'm curious like your thinking that
drove you to kind of think of this as a
strategic thing you should start doing
and then
how how do you feel it's worked out?
It's been a few years of you kind of
doing that.
>> Yeah, it's interesting cuz that kind of
lines up with um
what we mentioned earlier is when we
hired a Swift engineer, so I didn't have
to be always engineering and just
working on
>> You being gone for, you know, a week or
a few days or whatever doesn't mean that
the business stops.
>> Exactly right. Yeah. Yeah. I To be
honest, I can't really remember my
my thought process as to like, oh, maybe
this will be a good idea.
Um
other than just sort of
thinking like, oh, WWDC looks cool.
Maybe I've Maybe I should sort of join
in with that. It's been a really good
chance to um
actually appreciate like what we've done
with Teleprompter Pro, you know, it sort
of made me realize, like, oh, this this
thing has kind of grown and
and
it's it's done well. My mindset just
sort of
has sort of realized a little bit more
is like, oh, okay, we do have this sort
of position in our industry and on the
App Store that works really well for us.
Um but also things like I I wouldn't
you know, we've now been able to have a
relationship with Apple and the App
Store team because of
going along to these conferences and
things.
>> That one specifically would be WWDC, I
presume, right?
>> I've not yet been able to get a ticket.
>> Oh.
>> But But yes, you're you're right. It's
It is
>> in proximity with
>> Being in town.
>> Yeah, and like
>> I didn't even really know that that was
a thing
until recently that
I I kind of
understood that
Apple must work with some developers to
do these things, right? Um but I didn't
necessarily understand that like
it's not unusual for
an app on the store to have like a
contact with Apple and you just sort of
back and forth with some feedback and
things. Um
So, yeah, that that's been really cool,
but it
to be honest, it's just been nice to
actually have
friends in the industry as you know,
I've been doing this for like 15 years
and
I've not known anyone else in the same
industry. You know, even really in like
software engineering cuz I don't work
with anyone else.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so, it's been nice to have people in
exactly the same industry. Um and in
some cases at events like
running into people with the same
products. Like you know,
it it's been really cool.
>> Yeah, and do you feel like that's in
like worked its way into the business?
Obviously, you know, having some
connections within the platform
provider, you know, Apple is is useful
in that one context, but
have have you found like conversations
with fellow industry, you know, people
um both on the
developer app developer side and on the
the sort of film side,
have those trips contributed to the
product and the business in like sort of
concrete ways, do you think?
>> Yeah, I think so. I I I can think of
like one or two
kind of decisions that I I was on the
fence about
um and even like leaning one way and and
having had conversations with people,
I've
fully changed my mind and just sort of
um
I I want to say like they just made me
realize what an idiot I was being.
I had this this wild idea to like buy a
some
super expensive domain name because I
thought that was like
a big step in the right direction, you
know, that our next big thing will be
we'll have this cool.com
and then we'll grow in that direction
and then um it was um
Curtis Slopes.
What's his surname?
>> Curtis F
>> Herbert.
>> That's it, yeah. That's
>> Yeah, yeah. I I keep I keep wanting to
say Curtis Parrots, but that's not
Parrots, like the bird.
>> And he just said like what what are you
talking about? Like no.
>> I can't remember I can't remember
specifically what he said, but it was
he just said like what are you talking
about? No.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, and it's like oh yeah, well maybe
not.
>> Yeah, sometimes you need a mentor who
who's who's been in the trenches or who
understands or even thinks exactly the
same way you do, but hasn't been sitting
and stewing on this idea. Yeah, who can
have that clarity of mind to be like you
know, slap, like hey,
think about this for more than 8 seconds
uh in this other way and then it and
then it becomes crystal clear. Yeah,
that's interesting.
>> There's certainly been more things. I
just can't necessarily remember them,
but but yeah, just stuff like that where
I've been able to
bounce something off of someone for 10
seconds and just like oh yeah, of
course.
>> Have the the like film industry events
that you've gone to, those are very very
different than
uh developer ones, right? They're a lot
less personal, they're way bigger. Have
you found those useful to go to at all?
>> They're they're certainly like
fun to go to, like this big expo hall
with like crazy gear and people and
things.
>> That's on my bucket list. This is, you
know,
before I got into this, like Dub Dub and
Google I/O were kind of these two
conferences I really wanted to go to,
but the other side of me that's always
been obsessed with gear, NAB has always
been
at the top and Adobe Max. Like those are
like the actual the two big
uh industry events that I've wanted to
go to. So I I'm always jealous when you
say you've been and I see the pictures.
>> It It is good fun. Well, that I I've
made less um sort of connections there
just because of their sheer size. You
don't run into the same people ever. You
know, it's
took like thousands and thousands of
people. It's the only place I've ever
been recognized. They recognized my
t-shirt
cuz I had a Teleprompter Pro t-shirt.
So, so they didn't really recognize me,
but they approached me and you know,
they just like, "Oh, we
use Teleprompter Pro all the time." That
was
cool. I felt like a
celebrity for about a year after that.
>> And you've been running those or you're
like going as a
"Hey, we'll let you use our stuff, you
know, for free or watch you use it
basically to kind of get feedback."
>> It's more so
just a genuine actual like they've just
hired me like anybody else.
There has been one or two where we just
come along and just like, "Oh, we'll do
that. Let us bring our things and we'll
take some cool photos and things." But
but no, it's been fun to like actually
just be
like
doing that job for the day.
And people don't necessarily know, you
know, they wouldn't they don't know or
care that Teleprompter Pro is our
product. Um
but it's been really cool to
yeah, have that hands-on experience and
just sort of see
there's a lot of things that people
won't ever say, you know.
I had the idea to um
use like Xbox controllers to to do the
um control the scrolling of the text.
>> Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. Cuz you have the
variable speed. But that's not something
anyone's ever going to ask for.
>> Right.
>> People tend to ask for what they already
know about. It's like, "Oh, how do I how
do I do this thing that I've seen
before?" And so, "Oh, I've I've seen
that you can use these Xbox controllers
for those like
um camera robot arms. You've seen those,
right?"
>> Yes. Oh, yeah.
>> So, "Oh, we'll just use that for
Teleprompter. Excellent."
And it it's just maybe that's not a very
good example, but it's just really cool
to actually be
have the time to go and use our product
in real ways that's not just like on my
desk imagining how it might be. There's
this cool thing whenever I had Clement
Strasser on the show like a year ago or
so. Uh he talked about going to these
big gaming conferences and they would
always have these
like indie
sections where it was like booths that
indies could sign up for and people
could come and like
play their game, you know. Uh and it
with a game it's obviously easier cuz
it's like everybody at a gaming
conference is able to play a game. But
like watching people just actually use
the thing
>> Yeah.
>> kind of raw uh and getting their
feedback. And it's something that like
most of us don't really get. Like our
entire view is us using it or
uh and us using it in weird, you know,
non-normal ways, right? Or like feedback
we get from email or from maybe family
and friends if we're if we're lucky. Um
and And Adrian Eves who runs a community
kit, which is like an alt conference
alongside WWDC. Uh I think it's it's
yeah, I think it's free to go to. He's
doing it again this year.
Um and I think he's doing the same thing
again. He took that idea and applied it
to app developers. And so he does this
indie fair thing at Dub Dub. Um
where people can just set up there's
like a big
rectangle of tables and you can people
can just walk through and like play with
people's apps. And it was crazy to see.
Obviously like
it makes more sense or less sense
uh depending on on the app itself in
terms of somebody playing with it live
right there. Um but it's it's wild how
much just
having an opportunity to let people come
in cold and like
play with it. And and at an event like
that
>> Oh, they can't find this button. I need
to make it bright red.
>> Seeing them be confused about things
that you would just never guess that
they're confused about. It's crazy how
much of a difference it makes. And
sometimes even using the product
yourself outside of the context of
developing it
can give you that same thing where
you're like, oh, this made total sense
on my desk.
Uh but now I'm now it's it's in the you
know, it's in the
uh teleprompter
you know, physical device which of
course I'm sure you have sitting on your
desk as well, but
you don't have a giant camera hooked up
to it and you know,
focus puller and all you know, all this
gear and stuff and just seeing it in
that context radically can change
you know,
>> Yeah. Actually, one of the things that
we've we've done is um
we now have a studio like 4 miles from
my house with like three big broadcast
cameras set up as if we are doing
something and we're not um specifically
for that purpose
>> That's pretty cool.
>> pretend we're doing some sort of big
important broadcast.
>> Have you ever used it for you I feel
like you should do something with that?
Like marketing or goofy ideas.
>> I think on our user guide
yeah, if if you
you could Google it, but if you go to
our user guide, we've got like two
tutorial videos that are about 1 minute
long and those are shot in our studio.
It's like way higher budget than they
need to be, but it was we used our
teleprompter and we
figured out okay, how do we set this up
and you know, what are we going to do
for
I don't know, everything.
>> Now now
>> Yeah, that's been really cool.
>> Where my mind's at now is like, hmm,
when's the next time I'm going to be in
London? Like Oh, what crazy scheme can I
come up with?
>> you're going to be here, we'll come and
shoot something in that studio.
>> Oh, okay, okay. Oh, we need to make
that. I need to I need to sit there and
shoot a video.
>> It's on the train line from London.
You'll be perfect.
>> Perfect. Good to know, good to know.
This is the most valuable interview uh
launched episode I've done in a long
time. Uh
So okay, so we've talked a lot about
Teleprompter Pro, and you mentioned how,
you know, you don't have to be sitting
and doing the normal engineering
day-to-day yourself. Uh and you can
think about the product, and the product
can keep moving along even if you're
distracted by other things. And
something you've done very recently, as
in this week, uh is you've actually
launched an entire new app. And if I'm
understanding correctly, it's pretty
much your in the app. This is a, you
know, Joe Allen production. Is that
right?
>> Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. Nobody else has
had any involvement. To be honest, I
think it was just a little bit of
um
kind of missing out on that fun.
Certainly for like when we've gone to
these conferences and, you know, see
these people excited about launching new
things and
I sort of missed that
that fun of
building something new or or yeah, sort
of putting something out there that's
kind of experimental or I I don't know.
So, it was a
a bit of a um sort of hobby project, but
that kind of luckily fits a little bit
in with our existing users anyway, so I
can get away with putting it on our App
Store account and and and doing all
that. Um but yeah, it's it's been fun.
It wouldn't be possible without, you
know, Cloud Code. Um
We've we've we've done a similar thing
in Teleprompter, but it that was again
before um
LLMs
>> Yeah, can you explain what what the app
is?
>> Oh, of course. Yeah, sorry. Um So,
Captions, it puts
word-by-word captions on your videos. Um
similar to like Instagram and TikTok,
but the point being you don't have to
use Instagram or TikTok to do it. Um
And I'm hoping I can put some sort of
fun
styles and and animations and different,
you know, unique options in there that
that might not necessarily be possible
in on on other apps and and
certainly not worth doing on like
something like Final Cut Pro.
Um
Yeah, it's just kind of the
>> From personal perspective, this is
something I have to do very frequently
with the videos I'm doing.
>> Yeah, yeah, I I've I've understood that
this is a thing that people like or not
necessarily like, but they they they do
a lot and they it would be cool to have
a
a fun
>> it's important like so much, you know,
when you when video content is one of
the primary drivers of of your marketing
stuff.
Um
It's a lot of people their phones are
muted. They're on the subway or
whatever.
Um and people I certainly will sit and
I'll read the captions of a video as
opposed to listening to it cuz I'm still
interested. Um but making them more
engaging than kind of the default
ones uh that you maybe get for free
depending on the platform you're posting
to can make a really big difference. Um
And yeah, and honestly, what I was doing
I I now use your app. I have I've been
on the test flight for a little while,
but I frequently would sit and try and
do it on my phone cuz there's there's
obviously a lot of apps that can do
this.
Um
and often times I just
would get back to my hotel room or
wherever and open up Premiere Pro and
just do it manually all there because I
was a little picky about it. And the
thing that stands out to me with
captions specifically is that they they
just look like nice out of the box. Um
and you support wide screen which a lot
of these tools like Instagram has an
edits, you know, editing app. But it's
all it's always everything wants to be
vertical and a lot of my videos
depending on where I'm posting them are
not. Um and so just having, you know,
the fact that but very quick and simple
and the correction on
uh you know, it never wants to say
revenue cat, right? It always wants to
say revenue cap or or they're separate
words or that it's not capitalized
ready. It's really easy to just go in.
Uh you know, people should definitely
check it out. It's got a cool
instead of a timeline scrubber
uh you have the words in these like
pills
and you can tap on them to you know,
edit them. But that's what you scrub and
that actually scrubs the video.
>> I've never seen that before. Was that
like your idea of how to do this? Where
did that come from?
>> I remember
thinking to ourselves like, oh that's a
cool way of just being able to sort of
swish through a video cuz you really in
that context you only care about the
words, right?
>> Exactly. Yep.
>> Um yeah, so I I certainly had seen it
before. I can't I can't take credit for
that. But yeah, it it's fun
and it and I think it avoids
the issue that I'd seen in other
products where
they're kind of a you can do everything
product that you know,
we don't want to trim the video or add
images or do anything. It's just
here's the captions.
>> It has one job. It does it very quickly.
Um which honestly for
>> There's a long way to go, you know,
there's lots of things that I would like
to add and there's things that I know
are missing. Um but it's been really fun
to
just give myself that challenge of let's
put something fun and new out and and
try and do
the fun new liquid glass things and
something fun with uh foundation models
and and stuff like that. So yeah, it it
has been good fun.
>> There's two kind of big things I think
worth worth discussing here. Uh the
first just because there might be any of
our American listeners may have, you
know, searched in the App Store already
for Captions and not seen it. So it's
not called Captions in America. Uh what
is it called in America? And do you I'm
curious about that.
>> It's Recut.
>> Recut.
>> Yep.
>> And w- why is the why is it different
names in uh the US region versus
elsewhere? To the level that you know,
you can kind of get into.
>> We like the name captions and and I
think that's a good name. I I
I wish it could be called captions um in
the US.
Um
we we had a little bit of an issue with
an existing trademark which um
I think is a non-issue but
I don't really have the
uh what's the word? I don't want to say
motivation.
I don't know but so there was an issue
with
>> all of your time in US court systems
arguing that I think it's okay.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Yeah, so so I've been there personally
with with Dark Noise stuff as well.
>> Yeah, it it it an existing trademark
which um
it is a non-issue but it was
expensive both
cash and sort of resources and time to
to sort of
put the wheels in motion to just make
sure everything was okay with it.
>> Are you worried at all about it being
different names? Did you consider just
changing it everywhere?
>> Yeah, I did I did I did consider that. I
still don't know how I feel about having
a different name. Um
but the
the sort of nice thing that is that
because I'm considering this as a little
bit of a sort of hobby side project I
can take those sort of risks. Not
necessarily that it's a risk but like
>> You can always change it.
>> Okay, let's just try let's try doing
different names. See what happens there.
Um
so yeah it's called recap in the US.
It's called captions everywhere else.
>> And then the other
interesting drama with this app is you
were very close to releasing it. Uh what
when when was the first time? I think
in like January whenever we were talking
but it kind of got kind of got hung up
in the the the App Store process. What
what happened there?
>> That was
still a little bit bizarre, but I think
we
got to the bottom of it. So, I wasn't
actually necessarily going to release it
then. Um but what I wanted to do was
release for pre-order, right?
>> Ah, yes.
>> Um and it and it released uh earlier
this week um for like general download.
Um but yeah, it it was getting some
really strange rejections um from App
Store review.
Um I have to assume that App Store
review
is kind of different now.
>> Certainly now, yes, but I think in
January in particular
was when the the vibe code apps
mass flood kind of started. So, like now
it's a big deal and App Store times are
slow, but it's like
>> Yeah.
>> it's an issue that they've been
wrestling with for a couple months. I
think in January was when they first
started getting hit. Maybe even
unexpectedly with just the amount of
apps, you know, not that vibe coded apps
are by nature bad, but many of them are
bad and so there's this kind of
whoa, what are we dealing with here?
>> Yeah. So, to just like
to to sort of build the story, the
the app
uh in my opinion is not a vibe coded
app, like
>> Yeah.
>> I know what I'm doing to a certain
extent for how to build apps and and
work with Swift. Um so, it's a Xcode
project and I created all the files and
considered data models and everything
like that.
Um but I did use Cloud Code to sort of
do a lot of the
heavy lifting of just typing out a bunch
of stuff that I couldn't be bothered to
type out. And
um it certainly helped with things like
um the video rendering pipeline and the
and things that they that are beyond my
ability. Um
so, in that context, it kind of is a
vibe coded app, right? Um
so, there's there's that part of it. And
on the surface
um at least as far as I'm concerned it
doesn't appear to be a vibe coded app,
right? It doesn't have the purple
gradients and and
>> Yeah, well, to be clear, it being vibe
coded is not a violation
>> Absolutely not. No.
>> Um
>> No. But yes, using the app it feels like
honestly it feels like a Joe Allen app.
Like it's got that Yeah, yeah, you know,
I spent a lot of time doing nice Yeah.
Yeah, nice UI design and Swift UI in a
lot of cases and then UI Kit where it
needs to be. Um and an awful lot of that
was just me
doing my thing with to the extent that I
know how to do it.
Um and yeah, and you're right, vibe
coded apps are absolutely not an issue.
Um it just helps with my story for this
rejection, right? It was otherwise quite
normal um and it had a one or two
rejections for the
the standard thing that a new app will
be rejected for. So,
um I I think it was along the lines of
like um
specifically how the privacy policy was
linked things like that, you know?
>> Yeah, the typical I bundled them into
um privacy and terms and they wanted
them as separate links. It's fine.
Fine, you know, it's
totally to be expected especially for a
new app. They they seem to get a bit
more scrutiny. And then we got this
rejection for um under the broad
category of spam
um
which in itself was a bit of a problem
because it was a very broad rejection.
>> what it okay, if you read those
guidelines there's a lot that it covers.
>> Yeah, it encompasses like copycat apps
and um apps that we don't need any more
of um
um and then importantly it was um
template apps, low effort
you know,
this is not really you've not really put
any effort into this, you've just
put some code that you found up on the
store.
>> about to say, a lot of times these are
like GitHub repos that people
>> Exactly. Yeah.
>> You know, people make a tutorial and
they just download it, give it a
different name and
>> Exactly. Yeah, that's the thing that it
was rejected for.
And that's not the case, right? I
>> Yeah. As someone who's gone through a
lot of caption apps, I can assure you
your app does not look like other
caption apps.
>> Exactly. Um so, I had a lot of back and
forth just sort of saying that. It was
like, "No, no. Look, I've done
I've done these foundation model things
and we spent a lot of time on the UI
here and we're following guidelines here
and it's
it's not a template app, you know? And
it was just the same rejection coming
back."
Um
spam, copycat,
don't need any more template apps. Um
Yeah, so we
we had a lot of trouble with that.
Weirdly, it sort of prompted me to make
the app a little bit better. I was
trying to sort of
Okay, maybe they've got a problem with
this screen. I'll make it Yeah, I'll
make it a bit more
unique even though I think it should be
this way, whatever.
And essentially, it came down to a
couple of things, but we found out
because we arranged the telephone call.
You know, you can request a telephone
call from App Store review. Have you
ever done that?
>> I haven't and I think most people don't
even really realize that that's a thing
you can do.
>> Yeah, it's like a tiny line at the
bottom of your rejection and I think you
have to have
I I don't know, but I don't think it's
always there.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> And there's a
certain circumstances, a line will be
added to the bottom of your sort of
rejection email. Says like, "If you want
to talk more about it, you can request a
call here." And it's just a little like
hyperlink to a thing.
Um so, I did that and it was it was
great. I got a call from a real person.
Um
and it was surprisingly like human even
for
even for like what you'd expect for from
Apple. Um
So, what happened was he he
called and just said, "Yeah, I'm calling
about this Captions app." Um and he
said, "We've spotted it's a code issue.
We've spotted code somewhere in in your
package that's just automatically
flagging up as um
it
He described it as sort of downloaded
code or or
He didn't really use the word template,
but I think that's what he was trying to
describe.
Um
which again was kind of strange for me.
I I didn't really know why that would
happen, but it was good to at least know
that it was a code issue and not just
this blanket "Oh, it's a copycat." Or
"We don't want any more." Or "It might
be downloaded." So, it was it was good
to know that. Um
I get the impression that this person
genuinely didn't know exactly what's
triggering it other than he just could
see
a code trigger happened.
>> Right. I did clarify. I was like, "Is it
going to be something like RevenueCat?"
>> Or or some animation um library that we
using, you know, for the for the
you can do a little confetti effect,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> And he specifically said, "No, it won't
be RevenueCat. We know about them. It's
it's fine. It's not that."
Um And he just said, "Just have a look.
See if you can find anything that looks
like that." Um
And I really couldn't, but what I did do
was um I removed a couple of the
um agents.md
and other markdown files that I had.
I just dropped them into the package
even though they should just kind of be
in the directory, right?
>> Right. So, this is Yeah, this is like
for using with Cloud. So, it has nothing
to do really with your source code.
>> Yeah, just something where I clarified
the data model and like,
you know, make sure you do this and we
we're doing it this way and don't forget
whatever, you know,
standard sort of instructions.md files.
Um So, I just unchecked those from the
package so that they're not in the
delivered bundle.
Um and that got the approval.
>> That's interesting. So something flagged
because of one of these you know
>> Yeah, and I'm still on the fence as to
whether
the changes I made
um
were effective or
just having communicated with me and me
requesting that was a good flag.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, so it was an interesting ride, but
for a long time it was getting to the
point where I think like I might have to
just abandon the idea.
>> Yeah, that's crazy. It's a good lesson
though that like there is a mechanism
for
>> Yeah. Yeah, I I was just worried that
like cuz one of the
one of the reasons that comes under this
spam rejection is like a saturated
market. We don't need any more options
apps. And it was just an interesting
thought it's just like is the app store
now closed
to captions apps? And like will it
eventually close for every type of app?
And obviously I was going way down the
wrong road, but it was an interesting
thought to think like
wow, and maybe we can't you no one can
do this anymore. Like
>> It is interesting cuz I do feel like I
do feel like that like that was obvious
that rule is obviously in relation to
like we don't need any more fart apps,
right? We don't need any more like this
makes four sounds and does the exact
same thing as every everything else. But
you can imagine especially if the
ability to make an app becomes so easy.
>> Yeah, that that was
>> being saturated
>> after I'd sort of ruled everything else
out. I thought that maybe that's it
then. Um but luckily I had a last phone
call and it was fine.
Yeah, so that was my
that occupied my life for about 2 weeks.
>> It was a it was a happy day on the
internet whenever you finally uh
when you finally got into the store and
your pre-order was up. Obviously it's
out in the store now. It's been what? 3
days? 2 days since
>> Yeah, not long yeah.
>> So you know, we can't get into details
on how it went. Other than do you do you
think the pre-order concept worked? Was
it worth doing?
>> It's an interesting question. And the
reason it's interesting is because I I
offered the entire
full pro upgrade, everything unlocked to
everyone who pre-ordered.
Um
So, if you pre-ordered, you will never
see a paywall. You just get this
>> Did you market forever? Cuz I knew that
cuz you told me at one point, but
>> Yeah, I mean, I I told people
>> email list or something?
>> I I sent an email to to
um
our customers who I thought would be
interested. So, we we sort of segment by
whether or not they record videos in the
app. And I thought that's a
that's a reasonable um group of
our customers. And yeah, we I I used
that as a bit of
please pre-order it cuz you'll get this
thing for free. Um
I think it's nice to give a a bit of an
incentive and reward people for
supporting
my new thing. I think the first version
is going to be the worst version of this
product, right? So, you can have it for
free. Um so, it's actually it's kind of
difficult to know whether that was a
good move to do the whole pre-order
thing because everyone who pre-ordered
got it for free anyway. So,
>> True.
>> Actually, we didn't really get the
benefit
>> the benefits come in, you know, when
reviews come in and it ranking better
because there's more users, that kind of
thing.
>> So, yeah, we we got about I think about
10,000 pre-orders, which is great,
right? So, we got a 10,000 download day.
Um and from from what I understand, on
launch day, so when once it went from
pre-order to sort of general
availability,
um
we did
have a um noticeable
um boost in our search position. Um
I don't know if that is down to
downloads or like the the ratings and
reviews
>> figure out what's actually going on
there.
>> Um so, I I think it was a
good
a a good move. Um I don't know if it's
going to be right for everything. Um
but it was certainly fun to have that
sort of big wave of initial customers.
Um And it it was fun to watch us sort of
briefly jump above like Final Cut Pro on
iPad in the top three charts.
>> Yeah, grab your screenshots.
>> doesn't mean anything, but it's great to
like show off. I'm certainly happy if
that's a good measure as to whether or
not it was a good move. Um
And I'm hoping that's a good sort of
jumping off point to start growing from
and just
it's nice to just have that that um
project that I can sort of have a bit of
fun with. And now that it's on the
store, it's great to actually have
people using it.
Um yeah. Yeah, I'm excited to see how
that goes in the next year or so.
>> That's awesome.
Yeah, maybe uh maybe I'll have to have a
you on in a couple years as like a
follow-up, you know, for the this mess
that you've
>> as well. In fact, they'll be they'll be
rare in America cuz they say captions
and it's called Recap. But I've got some
exclusive pins. If you find me in the
wild developers listening
I have pins for you and and I don't
know, you can
give me a nice review on the store, I'll
give you a pin.
>> Perfect.
All right, well, uh I'm going to go
ahead and start start landing this
plane, which means uh
>> Excellent.
>> I need to ask you the question I ask
everybody in the show, which is uh
what's a person or people out there that
have inspired you in your work that
you'd recommend others check out?
>> I'm going to talk about a well-known
Austrian artist called Clemens.
>> Ah, yes. So good.
>> He might be my favorite person.
I I
I want his products and his sort of life
and all of his friends.
So, I don't know. Is that a good enough
answer?
>> I think that's I mean, honestly, Clemens
is such a great
Clemens is Clemens Strasser. There was
this sort of era of the the indie
developer scene that feels like it's
kind of lost. You know, like with the
great splitting up of all the social
networks, everybody kind of has moved
into their little hovels. And I'm in a
lot you know, I was fortunate enough to
kind of make a lot of these friends
early on when everything was still kind
of more centralized. So I'm in a lot of
these groups, but it doesn't feel like
there's as many people just
publicly
sharing their wins in a way where you
feel like you're going along for the
ride. Like most people
outside of kind of it being sort of
scammy feeling, most people I feel like
once they have a decent success, they're
almost embarrassed of it and they kind
of
Yeah. shut off a little bit. And I feel
like Clemens
I don't know, like he's one of those
people that every new milestone he hits,
I feel like I got to take part in even
though I have literally nothing to do
with it. He's very good at at that. And
then yeah, I You've met him in person.
He's just one of the like nicest, most
fun to talk to people.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh
Yeah, I think that's a I think that's a
good pick. Um
And if you want to learn more about
Clemens, there's an episode of Launched
from I don't know, last year or
something like that. Uh that you can go
to. But no, for real. He's he's great.
>> Um have you played Art of Floara with
volume on max?
>> With volume on max?
>> Well, just like
>> With the volume on, certainly.
>> Just going for it, yeah.
>> The sound design in all of his stuff is
so good.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
Yeah, he
he has a very
calming, chill
like uh aesthetic that I find. Also,
some of the best merch in the indie
in the
>> Oh, I know. I want a merch store. Have
you seen his
>> See the hoodies that just look cool.
>> Yeah.
>> Um yeah. Very good.
Awesome. Well, I think I think that's a
great answer. So,
I guess we'll go ahead and
and wrap this up. So, where can people
find you and your apps?
>> Uh so, you can go to teleprompterpro.com
find out about teleprompterpro
you can go to captions.app to find out
about captions or if you knew us it
would be called recap but captions.app.
>> Perfect. Awesome. All right. Well, uh
that's what we got. So, thank you all
for listening. Launched is part of the
RevenueCat podcast family now. If you
want to learn more about the growth side
of mobile app business, you should check
out our sister podcast. I don't know if
that's the right phrase. Subclub which
is hosted by my good pal David Barnard.
And uh
to learn about the easiest way to grow
and monetize your mobile app business,
check out revenuecat.com and you can
find more launched over at
launched.fm.com.
Um yeah, that's what I got for you. I'll
see you all in 2 weeks. Bye.